[eerie music]
[Marius] We traveled east,
over the mountains
and into the vast deserts of broken lands.
As the days passed,
my companion told me of himself -
that he had once been a great warrior...
and that a dark and secret burden
now weighed heavily upon him.
We traveled for an eternity
across that arid wasteland.
How long? [chuckles] I couldn't say.
And always,
a dark cloud seemed to follow us,
just over the horizon.
Finally, the journey ended;
we climbed the last ridge.
There, below us, lay our destination.
The shining jewel, Lut Gholein,
with the great sea beyond.
We made camp that last night.
Perhaps it was the warm desert wind
or the sound of the ocean,
but for the first time in many weeks,
I slept.
However, the dreams returned,
but these were clearly not my own.
I beheld a vision of a great man,
the Mage, Tal Rasha.
You were there, too, Tyrael.
I remember seeing you in my dream.
His brethren had cornered a great demon,
Baal, Lord of Destruction,
who had been set loose upon the world.
They attempted to imprison the demon
within a sacred stone.
Yet, when their attempts failed,
Tal Rasha selflessly volunteered
to contain the demon within himself,
completing the prison.
He instructed his brethren
to bind him within a tomb,
buried under the sand,
there to wrestle with the demon
for all eternity.
[screams]
[gasps]
[wolf yapping in distance]
Now you know what I seek, Marius.
This is my brother.
Sleep now. We set out with the dawn.
[wolf howls]
[Marius] The next morning,
we walked over the hill,
toward Lut Gholein.
I had no idea then of the horrors
that were in store for me there.