[eerie music]
[Marius] I did as you told me, Tyrael.
I found the Temple of the Zakarum.
In the deepest recesses of the Temple,
I found a dark gathering:
my companion, the Wanderer...
Tal Rasha...
and a Great Evil...
who could only be
the Lord of Hatred himself.
Mephisto!
I heard a voice then...
like a thousand needles in my heart.
[Mephisto] My brothers,
at long last we stand reunited.
The Infernal Gate has been prepared,
and the time of our final victory
is at hand.
Let the way to Hell be opened!
And the evil that was once vanquished
shall rise anew.
[wailing from Infernal Gate]
Wrapped in the guise of man
shall he walk amongst the innocent,
and terror shall consume
they that dwell upon the Earth.
The skies shall rain fire,
and the seas will become as blood.
The righteous shall fall
before the wicked,
and all creation shall tremble
before the burning standards of Hell!
[Marius] What I saw then
was not meant for mortal eyes.
[Mephisto] The Gate stands ready.
[Wanderer screaming]
[Mephisto] Now, my young brother,
the time has come
to assume your true form.
[demonic snarling]
[wailing from Infernal Gate]
[Mephisto] Arise, Diablo...
Lord of Terror!
[rumbling footsteps]
[bones cracking]
[Mephisto] You are the harbinger
of our return, Diablo.
Send forth your terror into Hell!
[wailing from Infernal Gate]
[dramatic orchestral music]
[wailing continues]