[eerie music]
[gate slams]
[voices calling out]
I heard later that he was defeated...
...and that the Soulstones
were destroyed in Hellforge.
All except one.
[sobbing]
Oh, I failed, Tyrael.
I couldn't do as you asked.
I couldn't enter that Gate.
Forgive me, Tyrael.
Forgive me.
[sobbing]
Marius, give me the stone
and all is forgiven.
Give it to me, Marius.
Take it. Take it, take it!
I'm glad this is finally over, Tyrael.
Look what the stone has done to me!
[sobbing]
[voices yelling in distance]
You haven't failed, old man.
You've done exactly
as you were meant to do.
However...
I am not the Archangel Tyrael.
[inhales]
Baal.
Lo!
Lo, lo, lo, lo! Lo!
[Baal chuckles]
You have done well, Marius.
Now I think you shall have your reward.
What have I done to deserve this?
[yelling voice fades out]
[dramatic orchestral music]
[screaming in distance]