[eerie music]
[Marius] My companion drew in the dank,
cold air of the tomb.
It seemed to...
strengthen him.
[wind whistling]
I stood in the doorway,
between light and dark.
What was left of my sanity
implored me not to enter.
But that voice was just a whisper now.
As we worked our way down,
deeper and deeper into the crypt,
I began to see a change in my companion.
He seemed to be gaining strength.
I could hardly see in the gloom,
but my companion seemed to know the way.
We came, at last, to a great hall.
[bats chittering]
[wailing echoes in distance]
[Wanderer grunts]
[screaming]
[screaming stops]
[wailing echoes in distance]
[Marius] It was then I realized
my companion hadn't been gaining strength.
He had been losing
what was left of his humanity.
[ominous orchestral music]
[Tal Rasha wailing]
[bats chittering]
[Marius] He moved with demonic speed,
and then... and then you appeared.
[Tyrael] Stop!
The beast contained herein
shall not be set free.
Not even by you.
[Wanderer yells]
[yelling fades out]
[bridge creaking]
[wailing]
Look what they've done to me.
Release me. Help me.
[bridge creaking]
Hurry. Please hurry!
[sword clanging]
[Tyrael] No! Don't do it!
[wailing stops]
[Tyrael] Fool! You have just ensured
the doom of this world.
You cannot even begin to imagine
what you've set in motion this day.
Go to the Temple of Light,
in the Eastern city of Kurast.
There you will find the gate to Hell
open before you.
You must find the courage
to step through that gate, Marius.
Take the stone you hold to the Hellforge,
where it will be destroyed.
Now, run. Take the stone and run!
[Marius] What choice did I have?
I ran.