[voices calling out] Marius!
Marius!
-Marius!
[ominous piano music]
[calling out continues]
[footsteps]
[lock turns]
[gate creaks]
[Marius muttering]
[lock turns]
[door creaks]
[Marius muttering]
[fly buzzing]
[whip cracks, man screams]
[Marius grunts]
[cheering and laughter in distance]
[Marius whimpers]
[plate clatters]
[whip cracks, man screams]
[stranger] So, Marius, at last I find you.
[enchanting music]
Tyrael. Yes.
Yes, now I... now I recognize you, you...
I should have known
you'd travel in disguise.
[breathing heavily]
They're... They're always watching.
[stranger] I've been searching for you
for a long time, Marius.
I was rather beginning to think
you didn't want to be found.
Oh, forgive me, Tyrael, please.
It... It wasn't my fault.
[stranger] Not your fault?
Tell me, Marius,
how was it not your fault?
The Wanderer...
Yes, it was...
was the Wanderer.
[flames crackling]
[Marius] My days in the Rogue Citadel
seem so long ago.
I sought refuge from my memories
in the company of other outcasts,
high in the mountains,
past the Eastern Gate.
Do you want something?
[Marius groans weakly]
[waiter groans]
[Marius] Oh, I fought sleep
for days at a time.
For when I dreamt,
the memories would return.
[Marius wailing]
Memories of the Monastery,
and the evil which had claimed it.
Dreams, memories...
I couldn't tell the difference anymore.
[door opens, wind howling]
Had the evil from my dreams
followed me at my heels?
How had he found me here?
[sword scraping]
How could this broken shell of a man,
barely able to carry
the weight of his own sword...
be the burning terror
which drove me to hide here?
[floorboards creaking]
[man] Hmm.
[man grunts]
[sword thuds]
[sword rocking]
[Marius] He seemed to...
to have demons of his own
that he struggled to contain.
[laughs]
[demonic growl]
[Marius] And he was losing.
[laughter distorts]
[clattering]
[laughter stops]
[demonic jabbering]
[demon snarling]
[Marius groans]
[demons cackling]
[Marius] As I watched, I...
I became convinced
that I was truly mad.
The terror, the destruction, the...
the evil I witnessed -
how else could I explain them?
Were these the demons from my dream,
or were they born...
within the Wanderer?
[demonic wailing]
[man gasps]
[swords clattering]
[waiter screams]
[man groans]
[Wanderer groaning]
[demonic wailing]
[bats chittering]
[pipe clatters]
[wind howling]
[Marius] Why did I follow him?
I don't know.
Why do things happen as they do in dreams?
All I know is that when he beckoned...
I had to follow him.
From that moment, we traveled together.
East.
Always into the East.
[flames whooshing]
[flames crackling]